<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Up in the Sky</title>
    <description>© 2017 Up in the Sky | All Rights Reserved 
</description>
    <link>https://upinthesky.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://upinthesky.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 12:41:18 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 12:41:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Loading ArduCopter Firmware to APM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This article shows how to load ArduCopter firmware into APM control board. This post refers to the previous “APM 450 Quadcopter Build” &lt;a href=&quot;https://upinthesky.github.io/2016/12/18/apm-quadcopter-450-build.html&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mission Planner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we need do download a free software called Mission Planner. This tool gives us the possibility, other than flashing APM board with different firmwares (ArduRover, ArduCopter, Arduplane), to control flight data, calibrate compass, accelerometer and radio control, program switches for different flight modes and even plan flight for performing autonomous missions.&lt;br /&gt;
It can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&quot;http://ardupilot.org/planner/docs/common-install-mission-planner.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. To install in a Windows machine just double click on the “.msi” and follow the setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/mp1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/mp1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that the package installs also all the necessary drivers needed by the board to be recognized by the Operating System:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/mp2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/mp2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/mp3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/mp3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything is installed properly the following message is displayed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/mp4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/mp4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the software has been installed we can connect the board to the PC through the Micro USB cable (be careful to have the APM disconnected from every other power source like the PM); then, clicking on Computer -&amp;gt; Properties -&amp;gt; Device Manager, under “Ports (COM &amp;amp; LPT)” you should have something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/apm_com.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/apm_com.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where COM6 is the communication port used for exchanging data with the APM.&lt;br /&gt;
After launching Mission Planner software, this port will be the same appearing in the upper right corner of Mission Planner screen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/com6_mp.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/com6_mp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not click on “Connect”, since first we have to upload the firmware on the APM; to do so, we have to click on Initial Setup -&amp;gt; Install Firmware:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/install_firmware.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/install_firmware.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since ArduCopter 3.2.1 is the last supported version for APM 2.x control board (in my case 2.6) we need to click on “Pick previous firmware” on the bottom right and choose the corresponding option as in the image below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/firmware_version.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/firmware_version.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that we just select the Quad version “ArduCopter V3.2.1 Quad” and confirm the upload activity:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/arducopter.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/loading_firmware/arducopter.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beware that Mission Planner takes about 5-6 minutes to upload the firmware to the APM control board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To calibrate magnetometer (compass), accelerometer and radio control just follow these good articles from ArduPilot website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ardupilot.org/copter/docs/common-compass-setup-advanced.html&quot;&gt;Compass calibration&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ardupilot.org/copter/docs/common-accelerometer-calibration.html&quot;&gt;Accelerometer calibration&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ardupilot.org/copter/docs/common-radio-control-calibration.html&quot;&gt;Radio control calibration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://upinthesky.github.io//2017/01/07/loading-arducopter-firmware-to-apm.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upinthesky.github.io//2017/01/07/loading-arducopter-firmware-to-apm.html</guid>
        
        <category>Quadcopter</category>
        
        <category>APM</category>
        
        <category>ArduCopter</category>
        
        <category>Firmware</category>
        
        <category>Mission Planner</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>APM Quadcopter 450 Build</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article I will show the build of a quadcopter made with a 450 frame kit using APM 2.6 with ArduCopter firmware version 3.2.1 as controller: this system performs attitude control and can be programmed for the execution of autonomous missions using PC (via Mission Planner software) or Smartphone (via DroidPlanner app).
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components list&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this section it is reported a list of the components used for this project with a short description of their most important features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HJ450 Frame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/frame.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/frame.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This frame is a nylon and fiber glass structure: the number stands for the length of each line of the cross frame, i.e. 450 mm (considering the distance from propeller center of rotation to the opposite one).&lt;br /&gt;
As the previous image shows, this frame has an integrated power distribution board (PDB) which simplifies the connections reducing the number of wires floating around the aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to have the red arms as the front of the quadcopter, while the white ones represent the rear (this is a completely arbitrary choice and depends on how the controller is oriented).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;APM 2.6 controller kit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main component of this kit is the controller, the APM 2.6:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm_circuit.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm_circuit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arrow with the “Front” tag indicates the direction that the controller interprets as forward.
It features an Atmel ATmega 2560 microcontroller and a series of sensors like gyroscope, magnetometer and barometer (the last one is covered by foam to reduce disturbances). It has ports to connect GPS, telemetry and power module. It features also a series of inputs and outputs pins respectively for receiver channels and ESCs (Electronic Speed Controllers) command signals.&lt;br /&gt;
There is also a port for connecting the board to a PC through USB in order to install/update the firmware or programming the APM.&lt;br /&gt;
A particularly important element on the circuit is the jumper JP1: depending on the chosen power configuration (using power module or taking power from ESCs) you have to remove it or leave it in place:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm_power_rails.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm_power_rails.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, since we are going to use a power module that distributes the power along the board, we have to remove JP1. Moreover, since the ESCs have a BEC (Battery Eliminator Circuit) we need to connect only the signal wire and leave the positive and black wires disconnected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kit, other than the APM 2.6 controller, includes the following components: CRIUS power module, GPS, telemetry modules (TX and RX), shock absorber and connection cables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power module converts battery voltage (LiPo 3S or 4S) to the proper stable voltage of 5.3V (with a maximum current of 2.25A) needed from the controller and delivers it also to the ESCs; it also measures battery voltage and current consumption, and sends these data to the APM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GPS and telemetry TX module are used to transmit respectively aircraft position and general flight data like attitude or battery consumption to the ground station (e.g. PC or Smartphone) where the telemetry RX module is plugged in; telemetry works at a frequency of 433 MHz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shock absorber is used as a mount for the controller and helps getting less vibrations so as to improve compass reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before mounting the APM control board on the quadcopter we need to upload the firmware like described &lt;a href=&quot;https://upinthesky.github.io/2016/12/18/2016/12/26/loading-arducopter-firmware-to-apm.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and perform magnetometer (compass) and accelerometer calibration following the links to the guides at the end of that article (radio control calibration can be done even after the structural build).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 x Emax MT2213-935KV Brushless Motors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/motor.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/motor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each brushless motor comes with a pair of propellers, one normal (for clockwise rotation) and another pusher (for counterclockwise rotation). Nuts have different colors since they are made to lock propellers in the opposite direction they spin (self locking nuts, so depending on motors rotation two of them lock in CW direction and the others CCW).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/propellers1045.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/propellers1045.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motors manual suggests to use the provided 10x4.5 propellers with 3S LiPo battery and this is the configuration we are going to set up.&lt;br /&gt;
The maximum Thrust for each motor is given by (0.850 Kg x 9.8 m/s^2) = 8.33 N.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as indicated in the manual, it is also possible to set up a configuration with 8x4.5 propellers and 4S LiPo battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 x Hobbywing FlyFun 30A Brushless ESC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/esc.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/esc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These ESCs support 2S to 4S LiPo battery and have a BEC that provides and output of 5V@2A, so we need to keep this in mind when connecting to the APM controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 x Turnigy LiPo battery 3S 2200mah 25C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/battery.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/battery.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are pretty classic 3-cells LiPo batteries with 25C discharge rate. They provide, for my configuration, a flight time of 8-9 minutes depending on the flying style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Walkera Devo 7e transmitter with Deviation firmware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/devo7e.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/devo7e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my favorite transmitter since it supports Deviation firmware, a community project that can be loaded on the Devo 7e by substituting the original software; its main feature is that it permits to bind to almost all commercial RC systems by simply adding some Radio Frequency (RF) modules (we will talk about that in other articles): in this way you can go to the field with a single TX controlling all your models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Walkera RX601 receiver:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/rx601.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/rx601.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a basic 6 channel receiver I had laying around; I will probably substitute it in the future in case I will need a wider control range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other necessary items for this build are reported here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expandable Sleeving Cable 2m (diameter 1 cm);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat shrink tubing 2m (diameter 0.7 cm and 1.5 cm);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Insulating tape;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nylon zip ties 2.5 mm x 150 mm;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;14 AWG power cables;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;XT60 connectors;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decent soldering iron, hot glue gun and cutter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can start the build by analyzing the power distribution on the quadrotor frame:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/power_distribution.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/power_distribution.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the image shows, we have to solder ESCs power leads to the board in the points indicated by the upper four red arrows, being careful to connect the black wire of each ESC, i.e. the negative lead, to the “-“ and the red wire, i.e. the positive lead, to the “+”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before doing that we need to solder the brushless motor connectors provided with the motors themselves to the four ESCs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/esc_connectors.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/esc_connectors.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To insulate the ends, we cut 3x4 short sections of heat shrink tube with diameter 0.7 cm and fix them around the connectors just by using hot air:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/esc_heat_shrink.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/esc_heat_shrink.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After passing ESCs power leads wires inside the expandable sleeving cable, that can be blocked in place using heat shrink tube with diameter 1.5 cm, we can proceed with the soldering:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/esc_soldered.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/esc_soldered.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a good practice to cover the power contacts on the board with hot glue just to be sure they are isolated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can now proceed by preparing the 14 AWG cable for power connection: one side of the positive/negative wires has to be soldered on the board, while the other one needs a XT60 connector in order to plug in the power module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also lock the arms to the power distribution board with the screws, having care to pass ESC wires inside the arm like in the following picture:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/esc_power.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/esc_power.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we can mount the ESCs on the four arms which is the best solution to achieve two objectives: good cooling of their circuit and distributed weight for proper balance; each one of them can be fixed with two zip ties:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/esc_ties.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/esc_ties.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After these steps, remembering to isolate the positive and negative leads of the ESCs (we need only the white signal wire for the reason explained before), we have the following result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/arms.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/arms.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For CRIUS power module connection we simply follow this scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/power_module.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/power_module.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can then mount the top plate using the screws included with the frame and fix the shock absorber structure with the APM controller on using some zip ties. This positioning has been chosen because as stated in Ardupilot website referring to the controller: “It should be placed close to the center of gravity of the vehicle (both horizontally and vertically). Generally this means it should be placed within a few centimeters of the middle of the vehicle and level with the motors.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GPS with its shaft can be fixed through one of the holes in the top plate; we need to be careful orienting the front of it in the same way as the controller, i.e. towards the red arms. Instead telemetry transmitter module can be positioned on the bottom plate. GPS and telemetry module can be easily connected to the ports with their referring tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding APM Inputs pins connection, we can follow up this scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm_inputs.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm_inputs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we just follow the reported connections, keeping in mind that we need to take the power for the receiver only from one positive pin (mid rail) from the APM, the other channels need just the signal wire (white).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm_inputs2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm_inputs2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead for APM Outputs pins connection, we can follow up this scheme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm_outputs.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm_outputs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have chosen to use “Quad X” configuration, i.e. the one highlighted with the red rectangle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motor 1 - CCW rotation with normal propeller;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motor 2 - CCW rotation with normal propeller;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motor 3 - CW rotation with pusher propeller;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motor 4 - CW rotation with pusher propeller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the following image reports, only the signal wire (white) from the every ESC has been connected to the controller:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm_outputs2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/apm_outputs2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we can mount motors and propellers, with particular attention to rotation direction and propeller/nuts type; the following picture shows a CCW rotating motor with a pusher propeller blocked by the corresponding red nut:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/motor_propeller.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/motor_propeller.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is always a good practice to group cables using zip ties in order to avoid collisions with the blades and have a clean result.&lt;br /&gt;
The following image shows the final product, which has a weight of 0.9 Kg without battery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/quad_top.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quadcopter_450_build/quad_top.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may notice pieces of transparent tape on the blades: they are there to balance propellers weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next steps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now we have the finished structure with everything mounted on, but we need to check if motors are rotating in the proper direction (if not, it is just a matter of inverting one of the three motor cables connected to the ESCs). By doing this, for safety reasons, remove the propellers from the motors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we are sure everything is properly set up, we can go with our first test and start tuning PID (Proportional-Integral-Derivative) gains.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://upinthesky.github.io//2016/12/18/apm-quadcopter-450-build.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upinthesky.github.io//2016/12/18/apm-quadcopter-450-build.html</guid>
        
        <category>APM</category>
        
        <category>Quadcopter</category>
        
        <category>Build</category>
        
        <category>ArduCopter</category>
        
        <category>Devo 7e</category>
        
        <category>Deviation</category>
        
        <category>Brushless</category>
        
        <category>Power module</category>
        
        <category>GPS</category>
        
        <category>Telemetry</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Up in the Sky” is a project that starts from my interest in Remote Controlled aerial vehicles, mainly quadcopters, airplanes and helicopters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, during the last years quadcopters have become really popular in a great number of applications: because of their characteristics such as Vertical Take Off and Landing (VTOL), stationary/slow flight and high maneuverability they are perfect for tasks like exploration, mapping, surveillance, cinematography and so on.&lt;br /&gt;
Even if these features are present on helicopters, quadcopters are preferred for these operations because they are more stable and easier to fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand airplanes are better if you need to monitor large areas since they can travel a bigger distance with less battery consumption (of course due to their characteristics they need to keep moving in the air).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this scenario, autonomous flight is a really interesting topic and research has done big steps in this direction: using sensors like GPS, barometers and cameras, vehicles can identify their positions in the 3D space so it is possible to plan missions that aircrafts perform in an autonomous way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a brief list of the main arguments treated in this blog, so you can have an idea of what you will find in this place:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build of quadcopters;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flight test of RC aircrafts;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transmitter modifications and improvements;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First-Person View (FPV) systems;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autonomous flight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really hope you will find this blog useful, so enjoy the reading and see you in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://upinthesky.github.io//2016/12/12/introduction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upinthesky.github.io//2016/12/12/introduction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Aircraft</category>
        
        <category>Airplane</category>
        
        <category>Helicopter</category>
        
        <category>Quadcopter</category>
        
        <category>Remote control</category>
        
        <category>VTOL</category>
        
        <category>FPV</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

